ARTYOM SUKIASYAN

JS SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

+374 98 33 90 20

artyom.sukiasyan1401@gmail.com

<u>Linkedin</u>

Github

Portfolio website

SKILLS

JS/TS

Node/Express/Koa

SQL/NoSQL/Elastic

Docker/Swagger/Nginx

Stripe/Payment

Unit testing

React/Next

HTML/CSS/SCSS

GIT

EDUCATION

Armenian Code Academy

2021

JavaScript BootCamp. A 4-month full-time intensive course

Master's degree

Armenian State University of Economics

2020 - 2022

IT in business

Bachelor's degree.

Armenian State University of Economics

2014 - 2020

International economic relations

LANGUAGES

English Upper intermediate

Russian Proficient
Armenian Native

PROFILE

I'm an experienced, hard-working web developer with a keen interest in education. Former professional chess player and trainer, I have 3.5 years of experience working with children as a chess trainer. I am a passionate to my work. Thanks to my extensive experience playing professional chess, I have developed an analytical mind aimed at optimal problem solving. Being a fan of my craft, I spend an average of 14 hours a day programming. I always strive to create clear and reusable codes that are easy to maintain.

WORK EXPERIENCE

JS engineer (remote, part-time)

Powered by love

2023-present

- Worked on integrating cloud communication platform to receive SMS on website.
- Worked on the integration of the Stripe payment system
- Gained experience mentoring juniors and leading projects
- · Gained experience working in TDD

JS engineer (remote)

Devs Software Design devs.ae

2023-present

- · Worked on a new version of the Arabian Gulf Digital Archives' website
- Worked on the integration of a special authorization system for UAE residents (UAE PASS system)
- Worked on setting up and integrating IIP server into my application
- Worked on customization of the server part and integration of external services in Headless CMS Strapi
- Wrote functionality for validation, parsing Excel, saving its data in a SQL table and indexing in Elastic

JS engineer (remote) sdc.am

2021-2023

The Software Development Company

- Worked on the development of a company management system with two-way database synchronization with several spreadsheets
- Wrote a small desktop application (using Tauri) that recursively analyzed the contents of a folder and produced a report in .xml or .xlsx format
- · Worked on updating and optimizing the company website
- Worked on the admin panel for World-Leading Biometric Authentication systems

Chess trainer

Ararat region chess federation

2017-2021

- Trained children from 5 to 14 years old, prepared for professional tournaments
- Participated in the organization of regional tournaments, was a arbiter in some of them

OPEN SOURCE LIVE PROJECTS

 Chess Arbiter
 Source code

 Chess Arbiter mobile app (on testing)
 Source code

 Ararat Region Chess Federation
 Source code

OPEN SOURCE FUN PROJECTS

 Chess Engine
 Source code

 Chess game for 2 players
 Source code

 Tic Tac Toe Engine with difficulty level
 Source code

